so to summarize the approach where we
have the conditional move instructions
we need a compiler support to do any if
conversion if the compiler doesn't do
anything the code will be just left with
a branch so this is not a fully
backwards compatible approach in that if
we add the conditional move instructions
to the is a we're only allowing the
compiler to take advantage of that but
old code will still not use these
conditional instructions this approach
will remove hard to predict branches so
if we have a hard to predict branch for
example through profiling we determine
that a particular branch is difficult to
predict we can perform if conversion to
get rid of it if conversion typically
requires use of more registers than the
original code because we need to keep
all the results from both of the paths
and also more instructions will be
executed as a result of if conversion
because we are executing instructions
from both paths not just one and also
because we need to add the conditional
move instructions to select the actual
results the ones we want to keep from
among the results that we have generated
from both paths some of these are
necessary in order to do if conversion
for example the compiler support is okay
we need that it will remove the
conditional branches that are hard to
predict so that we want to stay the way
it is but the need for more registers
for example can we do something about
that more instructions are executed
because we execute both paths this again
is okay that's how we do if conversion
but do we really have to have additional
instructions just to select the results
to get rid of this in this problem we
can change the rice a so that every
instruction is now conditional every
instruction computes its result and then
writes it or doesn't write it to the
destination register depending on
whether a condition is true or not this
approach is called full predication and
it requires extensive support in the
instruction set